(clattering)
(knocks)
(speaking Yiddish
(scoffs)
(creaking sound)
herschel?
(grunts)
(doorbell jingles)
-(doorbell jingles)
-Hello, Max, I'm dropping these off,
They were my Albert's shoes,
They shouldn't go to waste,
You should sell them,
I don't sell shoes--
And his overcoat
is in there too,
It's very nice,
you should wear it,
(doorbell jingles)
Well, I don't,,, You should
take your coat, I don't need it,
Um, $1 6 dollars,
So, where did you go?,
Oh, yeah?,
Who else was there?,
Thanks,
Hm, Sir, you have a light?,
-No, uh-- Do l--
-Excuse me, sir?,
-Do you have a light?,
-Sure,
Thank you,
Woman: Thanks, Sorry,
Yeah, I know, he thinks
he's adorable,
All right, cheers,
Hello, mate, You all right?,
Hey,
Well,
Morning, kid,
Morning, Jimmy,
(woman continues
talking on phone)
No that's an
attractive looking couple,
-Man: Bye,
-Yeah,
-Come on,
-All right, I've gotta go,
If they ever have a kid,
you won't be able to look
directly at it,
What about you?,
Max, you got any prospects?,
Me?, No,
Well, you should,
You're a good-looking guy,
Gotta good job,
That kid's got nothing on you,
He's got his own driver,
What, you've got somewhere
you wanna go?,
I don't know,
Maybe it's about time I figured
out my own thing, you know,
You're a cobbler,
that's your thing,
That's my father's thing,
And his father before that,
You should be proud,
Well, I gotta
get back to work,
Hey hey, how's your mother?,
Did you give her those pears?,
I did, She says thank you,
All right, let her know it--
Kids,
Hi, Is this your shop?,
No, it's actually my father's,
-ls he here?,
-No, he is not,
Well, I'm trying to talk to all
of the proprietors in the area,
Do you expect him back soon?,
No, I don't expect him
back soon, Can I help you?,
OK, um, I'm sorry,
uh, what's your name?,
Max Simkin,
Well, Max, I'm Carmen Herrara
from the Lower East Side
Action Committee,
OK,
Basically, we're dedicated to
the preservation
and rejuvenation
of the Lower East Side,
We're trying to stop
real estate developers
from converting the
neighborhood
into luxury housing
and retail spaces,
forcing the regular
people out,
-How are they forcing them out?,
-Money,
I mean, they buy them out
or they raise the rent,
How much do you think I'd get
for a place like this?,
That doesn't matter,
It does to me,
Max, we need people
like you to stay,
That's why we're doing
all of this,
Well, maybe you should've
checked with me first,
make sure I wanna stay,
Yeah, that's fair,
You know what, come here,
I'm gonna show you something,
Look around you, Max,
What do you see?,
-The city,
-Exactly,
The city, a living city,
And your shop
is a part of it,
How long have you had
this shop for, Max?,
Fourth generation,
That's amazing,
See, this is not just
a playground for the rich,
It is for all of us,
-Don't you think?,
-Yeah, I guess,
Good,
So could you sign this?,
-OK,
-Great, thanks,
Do you have plans tonight?,
Excuse me?
There's a rally,
if you're interested,
Here, here's a flyer,
Mr, Solomon is a wonderful old
man who lives on Grand Street
and they're trying to evict him
from this apartment,
OK,
Our office is on
Orchard Street, Come by,
You should really
get involved, Max,
OK,
(whispers) OK,
Hey, did you get her number?,
(scoffs) It's not that,
(woman talking on TV)
Ma?,
Mm-hm,
Ah,
(speaking indistinctly)
What are you doing here?,
-Break your eardrums,
-Did you bring any pears?,
I brought you pears yesterday,
Ma, remember, from Jimmy?,
Yes, call Papa,
tell him to bring pears,
-OK, I will,
-Good boy, How was work?,
Work was, uh, the same
as every other day,
Why don't you call
the Rabinowitz girl?,
T ake her out on a date this
weekend, She always liked you,
Uh, she got married ten years
ago, she's got three kids,
She's a pretty girl,
You should step up to the plate,
(chuckles)
Um,,, (clicks teeth) OK,
I will but not tonight,
You ready for dinner?,
Yeah, it's in the microwave,
(doorbell jingles)
Man: Yo, shoe man?,
Come on, let's go, man,
time's money,
What's up, man,
come on, hook me up,
Yeah, sure,
How you doing today, my G?,
Working hard?,
-Yes,
-Yeah?, Good, Good,
Can't knock the hustle,
Work hard, play harder,
right, player?,
God bless Americola,
(man chuckles)
Like that watch, huh?,
Sure,
Shit, got a collection at home
worth three times this shop,
Can always tell a man
by his watch, right, shoe man?,
-Four bucks.
-Four bucks?
That's the rate,
(scoffs) Fair enough,
(shuffling money)
Oh, I almost forgot,
I need these fixed, shoe man,
OK, What do you want done?,
New soles,
And I need 'em tonight,
We close at six,
Close when I get my shoes,
I'm just playing with you,
shoe man,
See you at six,
Right,
You sure
you can't come today?,
OK. Well, I'll see you
tomorrow. Thank you.
-Max?,
-Y eah?,
What are you doing down here?,
Using this old stitcher,
Mine busted,
Woo-hoo, look at this thing,
Y eah, It's something, huh?,
My pop taught me how
to use this when I was little,
It still works?,
Bit surprised,
but it's doing the trick,
Right,
That shows you what I know,
I was always telling your pop
he should sell this crap
and make some money,
But he could never
throw anything away,
Yeah, except his family,
He didn't
throw you away, Max,
(stitcher clicking)
Hmm.
Uh, my post
is up on the chair,
Oh, All right,
I'll leave you the news,
Jimmy: Hey, I'm going around the
corner for a beer, You wanna come?,
Nah, I've gotta wait
for a customer,
Ah, good for you,
Keep 'em coming back,
-Yes,
-Listen,,,
,,, I picked up an extra jar
from the pickle guys,
Oh, hey, thank you,
-Ah, Good night, kid,
-Good night, Jimmy,
(distant laughter and chatter)
(gasps)
(screams)
(gasping)
(whispering)
What the hell was that?,
(gasps)
Oh, boy,
Wow,
What the hell?,
(stitcher clicking)
It's the stitcher,
(chuckles) Wow,
(laughs)
(stitcher clicking)
(screams) He's dead!,
He's dead!, He's dead!,
(stitcher clicking)
Whoa,
(chuckles) I'm a woman,
Ooh!, No I'm not,
(blows) No I'm not,
Ten and a half?,
Yeah,
Nice,
-Yep, that's them, great,
-All right,
Sorry about losing
the ticket, pal,
Don't worry, Everybody does,
-I put tabs in the front and back,
-Beautiful, How much?,
That's 1 2 bucks,
You got it,
You look familiar,
Are you an actor or something,
Uh, no, TV reporter,
Yeah, that's right, uh,
from New York One,
the guy with
the two first names,
Yeah, Danny Donald,
Danny Donald, Wow,
My mother watches you
all the time,
Yeah?, That's great,
You look like you
but you're a little different,
You like that?,
You like being on TV?,
It's great, I love going
to work, I'm a lucky guy,
Yeah,
Here, It's my card,
Tell your mother
I said thanks for watching,
-Oh, yeah,
-Thanks again,
-Yeah, I will,
-(doorbell jingles)
-Hello,
-May I help you?,
Uh, what time
do you close?,
Six, It's on the door,
OK,
Do you want a haircut?,
No, I have to go now,
OK,
So go,
Goodbye, Jimmy,
It frickin' worked,
I can't believe it,
He had no idea who I was.
I could be anybody I want,
This is great,
I'm gonna hang out in Chinatown,
I have accent,
I have accent!,
(chuckling and speaking
indistinctly)
Max: T en and a half,
Got some big feet there, kid,
I'm big boned,
Thank you very much,
Where is the bathroom,
Ah, yes, to your left
and downstairs,
(indistinct dialogue)
OK, thank you,
(cell phone beeps)
-Excuse me,
-Yeah?,
What size are your shoes?,
Wha--
T en and a half, Why?,
Give me 'em,
-What?,
-Give me your shoes,
-Are you serious?,
-Yes, I'm real serious,
I don't believe
this shit, l,,,
(laughs)
Wow,
Come on!,
Oh, yeah!,
(stirring)
Oh,
(speaks Yiddish)
Yeah, those are for you,
Oh, so pretty,
I knew you'd like them,
How was your day, Maxie?,
It was good,
It was really good,
It was the best day
I've had in a long time,
Good, You work so hard,
How was your day, Ma?,
(chuckles)
I'm better,
now that my tatala is home,
Yeah, Hey, Ma,
let me ask you something,
You ever wish
you were somebody else?,
No,
I'm your mother,
That's all I ever wanted to be,
But if you could do
whatever you wanted to do,
what would it be?,
Um,,,
(chuckles)
Have dinner with your father,
That would be nice,
That would be really nice,
(machine running)
(humming)
(doorbell jingles)
Hi.
(machine shuts off)
-Hi.
How are ya?,
-Good, How are you?,
-Very good,
Good, Emiliano wanted
me to drop these off,
What does he want done?,
Whatever they need,
Well,,,
It's a ten and a half,
-I could clean 'em up for ya,
-OK,
Mm, Looks like
they need new soles,
Sounds good,
Here you are,
-Thank you,
-OK, Thank you,
(door shuts)
(car door opens)
(women laugh)
(hip hop music playing)
Hey, man,
What can we get ya?,
-I'll have a light beer,
-No light beer,
Here is the beer list.
Here is our cocktail list,
Why don't you check that out,
What's a pickletini?,
Uh, it's vodka and pickle juice,
You want one?,
Sure, OK,
You'll love it,
Enjoy, buddy,
Hi.
-I know who you are,
-You do?,
Yeah, I saw you spin
at The Jane on New Years,
You saw me spin?,
Isn't that what you call it?,
Anyway, I tried
to pick you up,
Oh, yeah?, Did it work?,
No, You went home
with that model,
You were all over each other,
Oh, yeah,
that's my girlfriend,
-lt wasn't your girlfriend,
-Yeah, we live together,
No, it definitely
wasn't your girlfriend,
-Well, how do you know that?,
-Because it was a guy,
Wha,,,?, A guy?,
Are you kidding me?,
It's OK, I don't care,
I think it's hot,
You,,, You do?,
Mm-hm,
Huh.
Hey, So, where are we going?,
I don't know,
Where do you live?,
Can't do that, love,
Boyfriend, Sorry,
Oh, Oh, Uh, OK,
Well, we could go to my place,
Just gotta make a call,
Who are you calling?,
-My mother,
-(dialing)
You,,, You live
with your mother,
Yeah, And she gets
a little screwy at night
so I don't want
to surprise her,
Really?,
Where do you live?,
Sheepshead Bay,
-(tires screech)
-Get home safe,
My name is Bond, James Bond,
and I live in Sheepshead Bay
with my mother,
Oh, hey,
-How's it going, mate,
-How are ya?,
-Beautiful night for it,
-Oh, yeah,
(beeping)
Woman: Yeah?
I forgot my keys,
Woman: You're a dork.
I'm about to take a shower.
(long beep)
(water running)
Woman: Are you there?,
Yeah,
Woman: Come here,
You want me to come in?,
Woman: Yeah, come here,
Oh, you gotta be kidding me,
What the hell
are you wearing?,
You are beautiful,
-Are you high?,
-No, but I wish I was,
Get over here,
Oh, sure, OK,
Thank you,
Look, I'm sorry
I screamed at you before,
It's just,,,
I get scared, And I need
to know you want me here,
Oh, l,,, I do,
I definitely do,
Get in here, cute boy,
Me?, Really?, In there?,
-Well, yeah, really,
-With you?,
Your friends can wait,
Oh, yeah, yep,
Yeah, definitely,
They can wait,
My friends can wait,
What?,
I can't do this,
-I've gotta go,
-Are you serious?,
Yeah, I know,
but I'm really sorry,
Why are you acting
like such a spaz?,
Oh, I'm not, I just,,,
Is this thing locked?,
-What's the matter with you?,
-I've got it, right,
-What are you doing?,
-I've gotta go,
I'm really sorry,
Um,,, Bye,
Emiliano?
Emiliano, come back!
Emiliano!
Danny Donald: I'm here
on the Lower East Side
for the Grand Street
Housing protest
-and we're here
with Mr. Leonard Soloman...
- Ma?, Ma?, Ma?,
-... who's our last holdout.
Danny: You refuse to go.
Can I ask why?
-I stay here until I die.
-That's Danny Donald,
-You're not gonna be
pushed around, I see.
He came by the shop the other
day, I meant to tell you,
How's work?
Work?, Work was something,
Carmen: Hi, I'm Carmen Herrara
from the Lower East side.
And it's Carmen,
And I too have lived here
all of my life.
Max: She was in the shop too,
... to stay here
and raise my family here,
and not be kicked out.
Danny: If people want to come
out and support your cause...
How about that.
We 're called the Lower East
Side Action Committee.
Please come by and get involved.
We would love to have you.
-Thank you. Good luck.
-Thank you.
I'm Danny Donald from the Lower
East Side for New Y ork One,
-I like him,
-Y eah, me too,
Who's Carmen?,
(car door opens)
Carmen: Max?,
Hi, Hi, How's it going?,
Good, You left your door open,
(scoffs) Can you shut that
for me please?,
-Sure,
-Thanks,
I'm delivering groceries
to one of our elderly neighbors,
-All by yourself?,
-Yeah, Max, I'm a badass,
Yeah, OK,
(chuckles)
So you like pickles, huh?,
-Yeah, Do you?,
-No, not really,
But I'm glad that you're
supporting a local business,
That's cool,
Oh, um, we need more names
for our petition,
Do you think you could
get your dad to sign?,
-Nah,
-Max, this is important,
I know, My, uh, father
took off a while ago,
He ain't around anymore,
-I'm sorry,
-lt hurts,
Yeah, it does, My dad split
when I was 1 2, Life goes on,
Yeah, right,
Yeah, I've gotta deliver these,
I'll see you soon, Max,
OK,
Come by the office,
Get involved,
Yeah, OK,
(mouthing)
(stitcher clicking)
Hey, Pop,
There you are,
Ma?,
(knocking)
Wow,
-You look beautiful,
-(chuckles)
Come on, it's time,
OK, my love,
(clock chimes)
Avram?,
Hello Sarah.
(gasps)
(speaks Yiddish)
Of course I'm home,
I missed you so much,
I'm here now,
But where did you go?,
I went for pears,
-(chuckles)
-Remember?,
Yes, of course,
I'm so glad you're home,
Me too,
(muted speech)
Goodbye, Pop,
Goodbye, son,
Ma, you overslept?,
Is that what happens
when you have a big date?,
-(knocking)
-Ma?,
Ma?,
Ma,
Oh, Ma,
Oh, no,
(sobs quietly)
(people chattering)
Max, Max, you should start
saving for a nice headstone,
She deserves a nice headstone,
your mother,
They're not cheap, Max,
(indistinct chatter)
Oh, it's good of you to come,
Thank you,
How you doing, kid,
You're gonna freeze out here,
I'm all right,
Hey, this was really nice,
what you did,
She'd have liked it,
You were a good son
to her, Max,
Look, Max, if your dad
was here right now--
But he's not here,
I was all she had,
I wasn't good enough,
Of course you were,
You don't know the half
of it, Jimmy,
Can't even afford
a decent headstone,
I could help out, kid,
You know that,
Why?, What have l
ever done for you?,
What have I ever done
for anybody?,
Look, you're hurting right now
but don't beat yourself up, OK?,
I'm gonna go
back inside, Jimmy,
Thanks for coming,
Max,,,
,,, I promise,
it's gonna get better,
Just give it time,
Don't do anything
you'll regret,
It's a little late
for that,
(machine running)
(doorbell jingles)
Man: Yo, shoe man? Shoe man?
-Yes,
-(machine shuts off)
Yo, where you been, man?,
I've been back and forth
to this shop all week
waiting on your punk ass,
I'm sorry,
I was sitting shiva,
Where they do that at?,
It's a Jewish ritual,
when somebody dies,
You Jewish?,
Yeah,
Lucky you,
-So who croaked, man?,
-What?,
Who died or are you just
making some shit up,
My mother,
Oh, man,
I'm sorry to hear that,
She leave you
any money, man?,
No, right?, Figures,
Ain't that
just like a woman?,
Do you have your ticket?,
Do I look like
I got my ticket, man?,
Just go back there and get my
shoes
before I kick some skin
off your forehead,
Know how much
them gators cost?,
No, I don't,
But you need your ticket,
New rule, shoe man,
you find my shoes by tomorrow
or you're gonna be reunited with
your mom real quick, got that?,
I got it,
(counter rattles loudly)
(door shuts)
(woman chattering indistinctly)
Hey, Mommy,
Want another baby daddy?,
-(baby crying)
-Woman: Jerk,
(he chuckles)
(men chattering, shouting)
(ATM beeping)
(indistinct chatter)
(grunting)
Yo, fatty at a party,
what are you looking at, man?,
Man: Ain't no
box of Twinkies, yo,
(elevator dings)
T ake the stairs,
Hello?
Jesus!,
What are you doing here?,
I'm,,, I'm sorry!, I'm sorry!,
-I thought you left,
-What?,
Why are you back?,
Oh, um,,, I forgot something,
Oh, yeah?, What you forgot?,
-You forgot to hit me again?,
-No,
Yeah, well, I'm taking
my shit and I'm leaving,
OK,
Do you know where my watches
are, by any chance?,
I didn't touch
your stupid watches,
I was just asking
where they were,
I have no idea, but if I did,
I'd take them and l'd
sell them shits,
You took my money, Leon,
and you know it,
I worked my ass off
and you just took it,
-Let me get that for you,
-Don't,,, Don't touch my stuff,
I was just trying to help,
Leon, one day you're gonna get
yours, You're gonna get yours,
Go to hell,
Man, this guy's a jerk,
(mumbling)
Come on,
(continues mumbling)
What the crap?,
Oh my,
What is that?,
(electrical zapping)
(groaning)
(distant siren blares)
-What the,,,?,
-Hey,
(groaning)
(choking)
I don't know who you are
but you're dead,
(hissing)
(electrical zapping)
(moans quietly)
Hi.
(grunting)
It's no use, I tied you down
pretty good,
Just tell me where you hide
your watches and I'll split,
(groaning)
Finished?
Look, I don't want to hurt you,
I'm not a bad person,
I just got to take care
of some things
and do right by my mother,
OK?,
I don't know who put you
up to this, fat boy,
but I'm gonna cut a slab
of bacon off your back--
(groaning)
That's rude,
And I'm not fat,
I am big-boned,
Oh, well,
Suit yourself,
But you'll be sorry,
(groaning)
-(approaching footsteps)
-(door opens)
I heard somebody's
not cooperating,
(muffled screams)
(gasping)
You done?,
I'm gonna make this easy,
The watches,
You gotta know, you can't hide
looking the way you do,
I'm gonna take my chances,
The watches,
There's a fake wall
behind the bathroom mirror,
Marsha: So, here's how
we're gonna do this.
I'm gonna take your watches,
tase you
and you're gonna wake up in
your bed like it's a bad dream.
Max: Wowee,
That was a great hiding spot,
-(muffled screams)
-OK, you ready?,
(fast breathing)
Be careful with that, man,
That's not a regular T aser,
That's weapons-grade shit,
I'm sorry, man, I have to do
this, It's the only way,
(knocking)
-Man: Yo, boss?
-Yo--!,
(muffles screams)
Oh, crap,
You scream, and I will tase you
and throw you out the back
window, you got that?,
Now, who is that?,
It's my boys,
We got business,
When they see you, they're gonna
just about break you in half,
What kind of business?,
Gotta pick up my money, bitch,
-How much money?,
-What the hell is it to you?,
(electrical zapping)
Fifty large,
Fifty thousand dollars?,
Hey, boss,
Hey,
New coat?,
Yeah,
Let's go,
Gotta make a quick stop, boss,
Got a little surprise for you,
I just wanna
pick up my money,
Man: It's on the way,
You're gonna like this,
(grunting)
Hey, boss,
Remember our old friend,
Patrick?,
Patrick the rat prick,
I didn't know
it was you, Leon,
I'm sorry, I didn't know,
We found rat prick
down in Philly,
Man: Bitch tried to run,
No more,
No more, please, please,
No more, OK, OK,
(gun cocks)
Bye-bye, rat prick,
No!, Don't!, Hold on, stop!, Stop!,
Stop!,
OK, boss,
What do you want to do?,
I don't know, Uh,,,
I've got to think about this,
Is there a bathroom
around here?,
What?,
I gotta pee,
(whispering) Oh, man, Man, oh,
man, oh, man, Oh, man, oh, man,
You should not be here,
(breathing fast)
You can do this,
You sorry for what you did,
rat prick?,
Yeah,
And you're never
gonna do it again?,
No,
OK, I believe you,
You believe me?, You be--
He believes me,
-Let him go,
-Let him go?,
-That's it?,
-Yeah, that's it,
Maybe take him to the hospital,
he's in bad shape,
Boss, he stole from us,
I know!, The guy apologized!,
Just do what I said!,
I'm the boss, right?,
Thank you!, Thanks a lot!,
Leon, follow me,
You stay here,
(opera music playing)
Good evening, Mr, Ludlow,
I am making duck ragu, First
time, very tricky business,
Do you like duck, Leon?,
-I don't know,
-Yeah, me neither,
I'm a Jew from Queens,
What do I know from duck?,
Are you OK, Leon?,
Yeah, I'm fine,
Good, I am ready to move forward
on the Grand Street deal,
I will need the trash
taken out before Friday,
You get the rest
when the job is done,
OK,
There is no margin for error
on this one, none,
None. You got it?,
Yeah, I got it,
Maybe you'll stop by
for some duck ragu
when you're through,
Holy crap,
OK, Ludlow, it's time,
Welcome home, Mommy,
Turn around,
-So where are your friends at, huh?,
-What?,
The fat kid,
the guy that looks like me,
No, it's just me,
Damn, you ugly,
And what have we here, hmm?,
Thought you were gonna
steal my watches, huh?,
(groans)
(gasping)
Please, don't shoot me,
Oh, don't worry, I ain't
gonna shoot you, she-man,
I am gonna
choke you to death,
(groans)
(choking)
(growling)
(screaming)
-Shoe man!,
-Hey,
-(gasping)
-(growling)
-(stabbing sound)
-(stops growling)
(spluttering)
(shoe clatters on floor)
No,
No, no,
Oh, my God, What the crap?,
What the crap?,
(quiet moan)
(whimpering) Oh,
Max: Thank you.
(heavy breathing)
-Hey,
-Yeah, what do you need?,
I'd like to report a crime,
What kind of crime?,
Murder, I killed a man
but by accident,
Why don't you have a seat?,
Officer: You unlawfully entered
the alleged victim's house?,
Yes, His girlfriend let me in,
His ex-girlfriend,
They broke up,
I think he was hitting her,
So why did she
let you in?,
Because I looked
just like him,
But you don't
look like him now?,
No, not at all, he's black,
And you said that you killed him
with a,,, stiletto heal,
Yes, that's right, six inch
platform, molded plastic,
but with metal tube
reinforcement.
Not great quality but it did
the trick, unfortunately,
Right, Right,
Max: The body is just right
in the living room,
You might wanna
stay out here, It's,,,
It's pretty ugly in there,
What the hell?,
The body was right here,
There was blood everywhere,
He was dead, I swear.
Wh,,, Where are my shoes?,
There was a blue bag here
with my shoes in it
and 50 thousand dollars cash!,
A,,, And a gun,
And my T aser,
Where's my T aser?,
It's all gone,
In fact, there was a whole cache
of guns!, What the hell?,
There's something screwy
going on,
We need to get
some leads or something,
Yeah,
I'm telling ya, he's dead,
I,,, I killed him,
Guys, I mean, should we question
the super?, Maybe he knows,
Sir, let go of the door,
But,,,
I'm telling you the truth!,
-(scissors snipping)
-(jazz music playing)
You gotta be kidding me,
What the crap is going on?,
(whispering)
How do you stop this?,
-Max,
-Hey, Jimmy,
You leaving?,
You just got here?,
Yeah, I've gotta go
take care of something,
It's peak hours,
What's so important?,
Don't worry about it,
What are you doing?,
I'm worried, OK,
What's going on?,
One second, What?,
You've been running around
half-cocked
since your mother passed away,
Will you just be
straight with me?,
All right, look, I took some
money that doesn't belong to me
and I'm gonna
go give it back, all right?,
No, Hey!, Hey!, Hey!, Hey!,
Whoa!, Whoa!,
Damn it, Jimmy,
Why'd you do that?,
'Cause I'm trying to stop you
from screwing up your life,
Your shop's closed half the
time, you're acting all crazy,
I'm not blind, Max, I know where
this is going, I've seen it before,
You have not
seen this before, trust me,
Oh, yes I have and you know
with who?, Your father,
-My father?,
-Yeah,
He was acting just like
you are before he took off,
What are you saying?,
Listen, your old man,
he got into some trouble
with some bad people
and he had to disappear,
had to make them think that he
was dead and never coming back
or else they were gonna
hurt you, hurt your mother,
You knew this all this time
and you didn't tell me?,
How come you didn't tell me?,
He made me
promise not to.
He what?
He said that I was
the only one he could trust,
What,,, the hell
are you doing, kid?,
New rules, Jimmy!,
You stay out of my business,
you hear me?,
Max, I just don't want you
to make the same mistakes
your old man did,
Maxie?, Max!,
Mrs, Greenawalt, I got someone
out here who wants to see you,
Who is it?,
Man: You gotta see
for yourself,
Hello, Greenawalt.
Hello.
Ludlow sent me
to give you this,
And, um, what is it?,
Your money,
He can't take out the trash,
He can't?
No, he can't, He's sorry,
OK,
And your name is?,
I'm Marsha,
And, uh,
where is Leon, Marsha?,
-I don't know,
-I don't believe you,
You see, um, Leon left me,
well, and you, in a very
difficult situation here,
If we don't get this little
matter cleaned up
I stand to lose an enormous
amount of money
and I don't like
losing money,
You don't have enough?,
No, I don't,
Thank you for bringing back
my money,
Brian will give you
your receipt now, Brian?,
(thud)
-Man 1 : You hungry?,
-Man 2: No,
Man 1 : You mind if we stop
to get some food?,
Man 2: Yeah, I mind, Brian,
I'm kind of busy right now,
Brian: I'm starving, Jeffrey,
Jeffrey: Well, you should have
thought of that before we left,
Brian:
I wasn't hungry then,
Jeffrey: We'll get something to eat
after we get rid of our friend,
We need to talk
about Grand Street anyway,
Brian:
Yeah, we torching the place?,
Jeffrey:
Yeah, tomorrow night,
You smell something?,
I thought that was you,
No, it's not me, Jeffrey,
Maybe princess
pissed herself,
(all screaming)
(tires screeching)
(screaming continues)
(kids laugh)
(moaning)
Hey, mister, you OK?,
Huh?
(all scream)
-(moaning)
-(screaming continues)
(continues moaning)
Don't eat me!,
Please, don't eat me!,
All right, All right,
I'm not!,
I'm not gonna eat you!,
Kid?,
(sighs) Kid, wake up!,
I'm not gonna eat you!,
Kid!, Kid!,
(heavy breathing)
Hey, There he is,
You finished?,
Yup, just in time,
-You feeling better?,
-Yeah,
I'm sorry
about the way I acted,
Oh, don't worry
about it, Max,
I should've told you
about your father sooner,
I'm sorry,
You're a good friend,
Jimmy, to him and to me,
How about a pickle?
Yeah, thanks,
Why don't you let me
give you a shave,
I think I'll stick
with the pickle,
Oh, crap,
Carmen: Mr. Solomon
is a wonderful old man
who lives on Grand Street
and they're trying to evict him
from his apartment.
Greenawalt: I will need the
trash taken out before Friday.
-Brian : We 're torching
the place?
Jeffrey: Yeah, tomorrow night.
M r, Solomon :
I stay here until I die.
Max?,
Hey, I think I 'm ready
to get involved,
How did you hear
all of this?,
I heard it, l,,,
Look, I have a special ability
to see and hear stuff
I shouldn't,
Max, I really need
to get back to the office,
I know it sounds crazy
but I'm not crazy,
You've got to believe me,
Max, I'm gonna ask you this
one time
and I want you
to tell me the truth,
Are you making this all up
just to get with me?,
What?, No, I swear,
I do think you're very pretty
but I'm telling you the truth,
OK, so who are these people?,
Do you know any names?,
The woman's name is Greenawalt,
Elaine Greenawalt?
Yeah, that's,,,
You know her?,
Yeah, Her company owns
Mr, Solomon's building,
Max: She's got a pretty nice
place upstate too,
Carmen: You went to her house?,
Carmen: This is the building.
Once he's gone, they can
sell the whole block.
It's worth a fortune.
Max: Wow. You really think
you can stop them?
Carmen : Of course I do.
I told you, Max, I'm a badass.
Max: Oh, yeah, that's right.
Carmen : Come on, he lives
on the third floor.
He 's the last one left.
See?, Everyone's gone,
-Hello, Carmen.
-Hi, Mr. Solomon.
This is my friend, Max
and we need to talk to you
about something,
Oh, come,
Max: How are you?,
These men, they said
they want to kill me?,
They said they would burn
your building down
with you
in it, so, yeah,
You believe him?,
Yeah, I do,
Hm.
Thank you very much for telling
me this, but I can't leave,
Are you kidding me?,
These are bad people,
Mr, Solomon,
they're not
messing around,
Max, my wife and I lived
in this apartment 45 years,
I raised
my daughter here, Sonya,
I cannot run away,
Mr, Solomon, where does
your daughter live now?,
Chicago,
Can I ask you
a personal question?,
Mm,
What size are your shoes?,
Mr, Solomon, I'm Elaine
Greenawalt,
It's nice
to finally meet you,
I want to make a deal,
I'm ready to leave,
How much?
One hundred
thousand dollars cash
and a bus ticket
to Chicago,
How soon
can you be ready?,
T omorrow,
OK,
Brian here will escort you
to Chicago,
Uh-uh, I don't need escort,
I want to see that you get
there safely,
Do we have a deal,
Mr, Solomon?,
-A deal,
-Good,
Ah, Come in
but take off shoes,
You're wearing yours,
It's my house,
Well, come on,
quit stalling, old man,
Then you don't
come inside,
Take off,
Just do it,
Let's get this over with,
It's all there, pal,
1 00 grand,
This is all you're bringing?,
What about the rest
of this crap?,
I leave it all behind,
start new life,
Brian: Where the hell
are our shoes?,
Oh, bad crime,
That's why I'm leaving,
What, you think
you're funny, asshole?,
Forget the shoes, Brian,
What do you mean,
forget the shoes?,
-It's freezing out, Jeffrey,
-We'll pick up some new ones,
Mrs, Greenawalt,
Greenawalt: Yeah, is he gone?
-They're on the bus,
-Good
Now get over to Solomon's,
I want you to sweep the
entire building
and wait outside
until morning, clear?,
Jeffrey: Yes, ma'am.
(stitcher clicking)
What the,,,?,
Jeffrey: Ludlow?,
I don't believe this asshole,
(distant siren blares)
(muffled screaming)
(muffled screams continue)
-(muffled screaming)
-Brian?,
What the hell
are you doing here?,
(screams louder)
Behind you!,
-(electrical zapping)
-(gasping)
I love this thing,
(cell phone ringing)
-Jeffrey: Hello?
-Any problems?,
-Jeffrey: No.
-Good, I'm ten minutes away,
I'm meeting Mr, T am in front
of the building,
OK, I'm parked right out front,
I'll wait here,
-Good idea,
-(clicks off cell phone)
Idiot,
Thanks for the phone, handsome,
(muffled voice)
Where the hell
is this idiot?,
Call Jeffrey,
What are you doing?,
That's private property,
-I'm visiting a friend,
-Who?,
Leonard Solomon,
He doesn't live here
anymore, he moved,
Really?,
Somebody should tell him that,
Oh, and by the way,,,
(car door opens and closes)
-(indistinct chatter)
-Oh, no,
(woman speaking
over loudspeaker)
Officer: Sir, can you step
over here please?,
Officer: Do you have a weapon
on you, sir?,
Wait, wait, I didn't do,,,
Wait, wait!, Hey, Solomon,
Solomon, stop!, Solomon!,
-No,
-Hello,
You're on the bus to Chicago,
I just talked to Brian,
He lied.
That's impossible,
No, not really,
I just gave him some of
the money that you gave to me,
What kind of game are you trying
to play here, Mr, Solomon?,
-You and I had a deal,
-No game,
This is my home,
I'm not leaving,
OK, let me tell you
how this is gonna work,
If you don't get up
and walk out of here right now,
I am going to burn this whole
place to the ground,
And then I'm gonna
send someone to Chicago
to find your daughter and throw
her off the Sears T ower tonight,
-ls that clear?,
-Yes,
That's very clear,
And that is good
for the television,
-For the television?,
-Solomon: Uh-huh,
What are you talking about,
you senile old man?,
New York One.
Hello, Mrs. Greenawalt.
-Danny Donald, New York One.
-You're who?,
You know,
that's Danny Donald,
Danny: Care to tell me
what you're doing here?,
What am I doing here?,
We heard you threaten to
kill Mr, Solomon
and threaten to kill his
daughter in Chicago,
I'm not in Chicago,
I didn't say that,
No?, Oh, because we have it
all on tape,
I could play it back
for you right now, Live,
I did not give consent to being
filmed for television right now,
You set this up
and I will make you pay,
Maybe they got duck ragu
in prison,
You son of a bitch!,
(commotion)
(doorbell jingles)
-Woman: Hi,
I came to get
Emiliano's shoes,
Oh, yeah,
-Uh, new soles,
-Perfect,
He's gonna be happy,
He wanted to wear them tonight,
Oh, yeah?, Going out
on a big date?,
No, it's boy's night,
Huh, No charge,
Really?, That's really sweet,
Thank you,
-Hi, Max.
-Hi, Carmen.
My favorite boots,
I busted the zipper and l
thought they were goners
and then I remembered
that I knew a badass cobbler,
Ah, well,
these are good shoes,
I could do something
with these,
Yeah, work your magic,
(chuckles)
So I talked to Mr, Solomon
this morning,
Oh, yeah?, How's he doing?,
He said he's having a wonderful
time and that when he comes home
he wants
to thank you in person,
Oh, well, OK,
How'd you pull it off, Max?,
Pull what off?,
Solomon, Greenawalt,
all of it,
Here's your ticket,
-Thanks,
-Don't lose it,
So do you have plans
next Friday night?,
No, why?,
You having another rally?,
No, I would like
to have dinner with you,
Would you like to have dinner
with me, Max?,
Yeah, sure, yeah,
Got a pen?,
Here's my number,
Don't lose it,
I won't,
Good,
Bye, Max,
Bye, Carmen,
(knocking)
-Shit,
-Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold it,
I'm not here to hurt you,
Bullshit, Leave me alone,
Wait, I'm not staying,
I just wanted to give you these,
Take 'em,
(forced chuckle)
You're giving me
your watches?,
Sell 'em,
They're worth a lot,
Why are you doing this?,
I'm sorry for what I did,
You deserve better,
Much better,
Hey, man,
you got a light?,
-No,
-I do,
-Let's go,
-(car tires screech)
-Hello, Leon. Remember me?
-Rat prick?
My name is Patrick,
you piece of shit, Patrick,
Time for some payback,
OK, hold up,
just let me take my shoe off--
Don't worry about your shoes,
You're not gonna need them,
-But I let you go,
-Well, we all make mistakes,
You look like crap,
by the way, Let's go,
You smell like crap too,
You been rolling around
in the garbage, Leon, hmm?,
Well, you should've stayed--
Leon: Hey, look out!,
Where am l?,
You're in my shop,
How did I get here?,
Here. Drink.
You took quite a knock,
What happened, Jimmy?,
You were in a car accident,
I found you, pulled you out,
Have a pickle.
No, I'm good,
Just take one,
I don't want a pickle,
I don't care if you want one,
you need it,
Just take one,
What are you talking about,
I need it?,
Pickles preserve you
when you change, Max,
They give you strength,
Otherwise, you get all screwed
up, jumping from body to body,
-You know?,
-Of course I know,
Who do you think got rid
of that putz, Ludlow?,
That stiletto heel
made quite a mess, kid,
That was you?, How?,
You see, the thing is,
I'm not just a barber, Max,
I'm also a cobbler,
And,,,
I'm your father,
-Pop?,
-That's right, Max,
-Max: But you're,,,
-No, I'm right here,
Ah,
(speaks Yiddish)
(kissing)
-Hold it,
-What?,
You were right next door
to me the whole time
and you didn't tell me?,
I wanted to tell you,
Yeah, but you should've,
I was all alone,
And Ma, Ma never knew,
She thought you were dead
or something,
I felt like I was dead, all that
time on the outside looking in,
Because you left us,
No, because I didn't have
a choice, Max,
-You had a choice,
-Will you try to understand?,
No!, I don't understand!,
I don't understand,
I don't understand any of this!,
Maxie, I wanted to tell you
so many times
but it was
too dangerous,
If it was so dangerous
why are you telling me now, huh?,
Because it's time,
it's time you knew the truth,
You're ready,
-I'm ready?,
-That's right, son,
For what?,
What are you talking about?,
Come to the basement, Max,
You need to see something,
See what?,
Your birthright,
You've gotta be kidding me,
As my father's shoes worked
for me, mine will work for you,
Who are all these people?,
Customers, They help us
to help others,
They're all labelled,
Derek Jeter?,
That one was for me,
-Pop, you made all these shoes?,
-Oh, no, no, no,
These shoes go
all the way back
to your great-grandfather
Pinchas,
He passed them on
to my father Herschel,
Just as I'm passing it
on to you,
It's a privilege to walk
in another man's shoes, Max,
but it's also
a responsibility,
I think you've
learned that by now,
You are a guardian
of soles, Max,
You are the cobbler,
This is your thing,
I missed you, Max,
I really missed you,
Pop,,,
I'm,,,
Listen to me, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry about Ma,
I didn't mean,,,
-Oh,
-Max: I didn't know,
I'm the one who left,
I made the mistakes,
And you,,,
,,,you did right by her,
By me, You did right,
Ah, (kisses)
It's been a long day,
What do you say we
close up shop and go home,
Yeah, let's go home,
Son, I can't go out the front,
not like this,
Let's go out
the back,
What back?,
This back,
Wow,
I don't believe it,
Believe it,
It beats the subway,
Max: Pop, this is yours?,
Ours, Webb,
this is my son, Max,
-Nice to meet you, Max,
-Hi, Webb,
Webb, we're heading home
to Brooklyn,
-Very good, sir,
-Did Jimmy have this place?,
No, no, no, no, I put this in
after I bought Jimmy out,
-Where is he?,
-The Caribbean, He sends his regards,
You know, barbers have always
been very trusted friends to us,
We never have
to worry about 'em,
Oh, who do we have
to worry about?,
-Dry cleaners,
-Dry cleaners, really?,
They're not nice fellas
and they're very powerful,
Wow,
Well, uh,,,
So, Pop, you mean,
we're not the only ones?,
-(engine starts)
-Avram: No, no, no.
There's plenty of tradesmen
like us out there,
some good, some bad.
And it's been that way
for centuries.
Tomorrow, we 'll sit down
with the stitcher
and I'll show you everything.
Max: Aw, man, that thing is
great, Pop. Where did we get it?
Avram : The stitcher? Oh, that's
a good story, actually.
A long time ago, on the coldest
of winter nights,
a vagrant came knocking
at the door of our shop.
Your great-great-grandfather
gave him shelter
when no one else would.
He fed the man,
mended his shoes...